digitalunite.com 2019-10-24

# Our privacy policy | Digital Unite

Digital Unite Ltd is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This privacy policy tells you what to expect when we collect personal information.

We are the leading provider of Digital Champion training, which it delivers via its online training platform The Digital Champions Network (DCN). DU operates in the UK.

Our registered office is at:

18 Hundred Acres Rd, Wickham, Fareham PO17 6JB

We serve housing associations, councils, charities, corporates and the general public via the following online platforms. Full details about us and our product can be found here: _<http://www.digitalunite.com/about/>_

Digital Unite website

([https://www.digitalunite.com](https://www.digitalunite.com/))

| 

Our website provides:

  * Freely accessible technology guides to the general public
  * Information about our Digital Champion service
  * Industry insights

---|---  
  
The Digital Champions Network ([https://www.digitalchampionsnetwork.com](https://www.digitalchampionsnetwork.com/))

| 

The DCN provides:

  * A unique training and support community for aspiring and experienced Digital Champions
  * Management information for organisations who are running dedicated Digital Champion projects
  * Membership sits behind a log-in: the DCN is not freely available to the general public.

By visiting our websites or using our services, you agree that we can use your personal information for the purposes described in this privacy policy.

## **What our privacy policy covers**

  * This privacy policy covers use of the Digital Unite website and the Digital Champions Network.
  * It does not cover the links within our websites linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.
  * It does not cover how a Digital Champion’s data is used by their sponsoring organisation. Digital Champions can get this information from their sponsoring organisation directly.

## **Definitions**

When we refer to 'we', 'us', and 'our', we mean Digital Unite Ltd.

We also refer to 'personal information' and by this we mean information which relates to or is obviously about you, or from which you can be identified.

When we refer to a ‘sponsoring' organisation’ or ‘client organisation’, we mean the organisation that is sponsoring a Digital Champion’s membership of the Digital Champions Network and has acquired this membership from Digital Unite Ltd.

## Processing your personal information

We may collect personal information about:

  * visits to our websites
  * enquiries about our products or services
  * information contained in enquiry, feedback or event-booking forms, including through our 'get in touch' forms on both the Digital Unite and Digital Champions Network websites.
  * information you provide in application forms, surveys or in feedback
  * If you contact our ‘live chat’ support through the Digital Champions Network, these live chats may be recorded and retained for a limited period for training and monitoring purposes and to help improve our services. Telephone calls to and from Digital Unite Ltd are never recorded.

In addition, we collect the following data about Digital Champions who use our Digital Champions Network service.

* _indicates a mandatory field_

1.Digital Champion’s relation to their sponsoring organisation*

|  | 

11.Level of education  
  
---|---|---  
  
2.First name*

|  | 

12.Disability  
  
3.Last name*

|  | 

13.Ethnicity  
  
4.Username*

|  | 

14.’About me’ profile text  
  
5.Email address*

|  | 

15\. Existing digital skill level  
  
6.Password*

|  | 

16.Existing Digital Champion skills  
  
7.Postcode

|  | 

17.Motivation for being a Digital Champion  
  
8.Gender

|  | 

18.eLearning courses started and completed  
  
9.Age

|  | 

19.Forum contributions  
  
10.First language

|  | 

20.Requests for support submitted via the live chat (Please note that the live chat service is hosted by a 3rd party platform called Intercom. Their security policy complies with the EU/US privacy shield and you can read it here: <https://www.intercom.com/security>)  
  
|  |   
  
The Digital Champions Network can also monitor a Digital Champion’s session with an end learner. The data captured here is specified by the Digital Champion’s sponsoring organisation but may include:

1.Learner’s name*         

|   | 

5.Key challenge from session  
  
---|---|---  
  
2.Date of session*

|   | 

6.Session venue or learner postcode  
  
3.Topics covered*

|  | 

7.Any other comments  
  
4.Key highlight from the session          

|  |   
  
## **Uses made of your personal information**

We use personal information to:

  * ensure that content from our websites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device
  * provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes
  * carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us including the delivery of Digital Champion training
  * award Digital Champions for their activities helping end learners
  * allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so, and
  * notify you about changes to our products and services.

## **How long we keep your personal information**

We will keep information for a reasonable amount of time in order to perform the purposes listed above. We only keep your information for as long as necessary.

We keep personal information for 2 years after last contact with you, unless you are part of a member organisation that has ceased their membership of the Digital Champions Network. In this situation, all personal information is deleted within 6 months of the end of the membership.

## **Security**

We take appropriate organisational and technical security measures to protect personal information that we hold against unauthorised disclosure or unlawful processing. Personal information transmitted to our websites is held on secure servers and encrypted. However, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our websites; any transmission is at your own risk.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

## **Use of cookies**

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small data files containing unique identifiers, which are sent to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are used to improve your online experience to:

  * Make our websites operate as you'd expect
  * Remember your settings during and between visits
  * Improve the speed/security of the site
  * Allow you to share pages with social networks like Facebook
  * Continuously improve our websites for you
  * Make our marketing more efficient.

**Types of cookies**

_Category 1 Cookies_

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. User consent is not required for the delivery of those cookies which are strictly necessary to provide services requested by the user.

_Category 2 Cookies_

These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for e.g. which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works.

Web analytics that use cookies to gather data to enhance the performance of a website fall into this category. For example, they may be used for testing designs and ensuring a consistent look and feel is maintained for the user.

_Definitions supplied by the International Chamber of Commerce 'ICC UK Cookie Guide' April 2012._

We use these two types of cookie and they are kept for up to 2 years.

_Social Website Cookies_

So you can easily "Like" or share our content on the likes of Facebook and Twitter we have included sharing buttons on our websites.

The privacy implications on this will vary from social network to social network and will be dependent on the privacy settings you have chosen on these networks.

For information on how to delete cookies, please refer to: <http://www.wikihow.com/Clear-Your-Browser's-Cookies>

We do not use cookies to:

  * Collect any personally identifiable information without your express permission
  * Collect any sensitive information without your express permission
  * Pass personally identifiable data to third parties
  * Pay sales commissions

## **Disclosure of personal information**

  * Digital Unite sells membership of the Digital Champions Network to individuals and to client organisations. Digital Champions self-enrol on the Digital Champions Network using a voucher code that is created by Digital Unite. Where a client organisation buys a membership, they can then recruit their Digital Champions and distribute the voucher codes which Digital Unite has provided to them. Only the client organisation can access their own Digital Champions’ personal information, in addition to Digital Unite.
  * We may use third parties to process your personal information on our behalf. Where we do so, we ensure that they process information in accordance with our confidentiality and security requirements as well as in accordance with data protection requirements.
  * We may also disclose your personal information where we are required by law.
  * We may disclose your personal information (to the extent necessary) to third parties in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets.

## **Marketing**

We will only send you marketing information where you have provided your consent to receive it. You have the right to ask us to stop processing your personal information for marketing purposes by emailing: [du@digitalunite.com](mailto:du@digitalunite.com) or telephoning 0800 228 9272.

You can unsubscribe from any e-newsletters by clicking on the link within the email that has been sent to you.

## **Access to your personal information**

You can find out if we hold any personal information by making a 'subject access request' under the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679. If we do hold information about you we will:

  * give you a description of it;
  * tell you why we are holding it;
  * tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

For all requests for any personal information we may hold you need to put the request in writing to the Data Protection Officer, by emailing [du@digitalunite.com](mailto:du@digitalunite.com). We will respond to all subject access requests within 40 days of having received the request.

## **Changes to our privacy policy**

We keep our privacy policy under regular review.

Last review: April 2018

## **Contact**

If you would like to know more about anything in this privacy policy, please email us at [du@digitalunite.com](mailto:du@digitalunite.com).

##  The Information Commissioner

The Information Commissioner is the UK's independent body set up to uphold information rights.

If you would like to know more about your rights under the Data Protection law, and what you should expect from us, visit the [Information Commissioner’s website](https://ico.org.uk/).
